Bfff... Detention. Uh!
留堂 唉
I love this song! Yea... Braagagaga...
我爱死这首歌了！
Miko.
神子
I thought you had a history report to do.
你不是要做历史报告吗？
Did detention end early?
老师提前下课了？
It did for me.
我自己提前的
Aho, here comes teacher,
啊喔 老师追出来了
and she doesn't look happy.
她脸色不太好
Step on it, Bulkhead!
快踩油门 隔板！
Eh, Miko.
唉 神子啊
Miko, I'm supposed to be your guardian,
神子 我是你的保镖
not your get-away car.
不是你的逃学专车
You can't just cut detention.
你可不能逃课啊
What if your parents found out?
你父母知道了怎么办？
They live in Tokyo, remember?
他们在东京呢 忘了吗？
And don't even worry about host parents.
寄宿监护人就更不用说了
I think I scared them.
他们被我吓坏了
Miko, listen.
神子 听着
If you fail high school. You can't go to... uh.. to the...
如果你中学肄业 就没法进那个…
Uh... Una... i... Wait wait wait what's that word again?
大…阿…西…约… 那个词儿怎么说来着？
Uh, college?
呃 大学吗？
You sound like my parents.
你说话跟我父母一样
Aren't they Japanese?
他们不是日本人吗？
They make speak a different language,
你们的语言是不一样
but you say the same things.
可内容都是老一套
Because we want the best for you,
因为我们都是为你好
and that means making sure you go to school, not jail.
也就是说 希望你去上学 而不是坐牢
Uho, what did you do?
啊喔 你又闯什么祸了？
Look, Miko, before I became a warrior,
听着 神子 我在成为战士之前
I was a laborer, construction.
是个工人 建筑工
I can build stuff, I can break stuff. And that's it.
我能造东西 也能拆东西 可别的都不会
I love breaking stuff.
我喜欢拆东西！
I want to be just like you, Bulk.
我想和你一样 小隔
Uh, why would you want to be like me,
呃 干嘛要跟我一样
when you can be a... a medic, like Rachet.
其实你可以当个…医生 就像救护车
I'm detecting a fresh energon pos,
我发现了一个新的能量脉冲
from a nation called Greece.
地点是一个叫希腊的国家
An ancient city, quite historical, I belief.
是座古城 历史应该很悠久
Ancient Greece, uh?
古希腊是吗？
A field trip!
又要实地考察了
It's about time, Knockout.
来的正是时候 击倒
I do not enjoy being kept waiting.
我不喜欢被人放鸽子
Ahh, it was a long drive, Starscream.
路程很远的 红蜘蛛
I'm still picking bugs out of my grille.
我现在还在清理保险杠上的垃圾呢
Yes, right. You're one of those.
是的 没错 你也是其中之一
Come again?
什么意思？
Never understood why any self-respecting Decepticon would choose automobile as his vehicle mode.
真想不通 一个有自尊的霸天虎 怎么会选择汽车当作伪装形态呢
when it could have flight.
选飞机不是更潇洒吗？
I like the way I look in steel belted radials.
我喜欢那种钢丝子午线轮胎
I take it that lord Megatron requires a laboratory assist?
我听说 威震天陛下需要点医疗协助？
You might say that.
可以这么说
Here we are.
我们到了
S-weet!
太棒了！
So, what are we doing in Greek old ville?
好了 我们来希腊古镇要干嘛？
I am scouting energon.
我要搜索能量
You are doing research for your history report.
你去准备你的历史报告
You punked me Bulk? Not cool!
你敢阴我 老隔？没劲！
Signal strong.
信号很强
Excavation site!
是个发掘遗址
I know construction.
我对建筑很在行
According to my scanner humans had energon vans.
从扫描结果看来 人类挖到了能量矿
And they don't even know it.
可他们对此一无所知
That's Cybertronian.
那是塞博特恩的东西
Sadly, our inevitably former lord Megatron has been like this for some time.
很可惜 我们的前任领袖威震天 已经昏死很久了
But the crew took a vote and it was decided that
经过全体人员的投票表决
an expert might put him on the road to recovery.
希望找到一个专家 让他恢复元气
I've done plenty of body-works, Starscream,
我的确对身体结构有点研究 红蜘蛛
but I'm at breaking them than fixing them.
但我擅长的是拆毁 不是复原
Uh, would help if I had my assistant.
要是我的助手在就好了
I summoned both of you. Where is he?
我把你们俩都召来了 他人呢？
We were halt on an energon trail when you called.
你呼叫的时候 我们正在考察一处能量踪迹
Breakdown will show when he's through scouting it.
侦察完毕 打击就会来了
Why would ancient Greeks paint of energon harvester.
古希腊人为什么要画能量收割器？
You know what that round thing is?
你认识那个圆球吗？
You are smarter than you led on.
你好像开窍了
But even dumber than he looks.
但开窍得有点晚了
Breakdown.
打击
Hehehe, miss me?
哼哼 想我了吗？
Like rest of my undercarriage.
我会想念车盘的铁锈吗？
You know this lunkhead?
你认识那个呆子？
We have a history.
我们打过交道
And you have a pet.
你还养了个宠物
Does it play catch?
它会玩接球吗？
Catch!
接着！
Miko, stay down!
神子 趴下！
Oops.
哎呀
Hope that pretty picture wasn't too important.
但愿那风景画不算太值钱
Told you I'm good at breaking things.
我说过 我很会拆东西
I always have you back, Bulk.
我替你留了一手 老隔
Got us a picture of the picture.
我把那幅画拍下来了
It is indeed an energon harvester.
的确是能量收割器
A powerful tool created by the ancients
古汽车人发明了这个强大的工具
to remove raw energon from any source.
用来吸取各种原生能量
Greek gods knew Autobots?
希腊众神也认识汽车人吗？
No.
不
The ancients often use the art of a given era to conceal messages.
古人当时通常用画来隐藏信息
This fresco is likely a sign post indicating a harvester's location,
这幅壁画很可能指出了收割器所在的位置
hidden somewhere on this planet.
就在这个星球的某个角落
Uh, Optimus.
呃 擎天柱
If the harvester removes energon from anything,
如果收割器能吸取一切能量
and you all have energon pumping inside you...
那你们体内的能量怎么办？
In Decepticon hands,
如果落入霸天虎之手
the harvester would be a devastating weapon.
收割器将变成毁灭性的武器
See, you are a genius to total that painting.
你看 你毁掉那幅画太明智了
Miko's not wrong.
神子说的没错
How can the Cons find the harvester without the Fresco?
没有了壁画 虎子们去哪儿找收割器？
With high speed internet?
当然是高速互联网了
If we do an image search for Greek God and Gold orb,
在图片中搜索希腊神祗和金球
this pops up.
就能搜到这个
It's in a museum.
在一个博物馆里
That the real deal?
那是真货吗？
Contact Agent Fowler.
联系福勒探员
You've reached Special Agent William Fowler.
这是威廉・福勒特工的电话号码
I've currently on an intensive training retreat.
我正在进行秘密强化训练
And I'm not available until Tuesday.
周二之前不会回来
I hate talking to machines.
我讨厌跟机器说话
Without Agent Fowler's direct aid,
既然福勒探员没办法出面
we will have to confiscate the harvester on our own.
我们就要亲自没收收割器了
Well, well, well, confiscate?
喔…“没收”？
As in steal museum property?
那是盗窃博物馆财产
That sounds illegal.
听起来是…非法行为
I do not wish to break human law.
我也不想触犯人类法律
But once the Decepticons learn of the harvester's location,
可一旦霸天虎得知收割器的位置
they will not hesitate to obtain it by any means necessary.
他们会不惜任何手段 把它据为己有
We must act covertly.
我们必须隐蔽行动
But, covertly and giant robots don't really go together.
让巨型机器人执行隐蔽行动实在不靠谱
Museums are public.
博物馆是公共场所
And they have guards and security cameras.
里面有保安 还有安全摄像头
No problem!
没问题！
We are small enough to sneak in,
我们个子小 可以溜进去
and we are not a government secret.
而且我们不是秘密势力
Miko, I'm not sure that's wise.
神子 我觉得这么做不太明智
But it may be our best option, Bulkhead.
但也许是我们的最佳选择 隔板
The longer we debate,
我们争论得越久
the more time we give to the Decepticons.
给霸天虎留下的时间就越多
And I'm afraid Megatron's well-being will have to wait.
恐怕威震天的康复工作要先放在一边了
It's harvest time.
收割的时候到了
Autobots, confirm position.
汽车人 确认位置
Westward held.
西侧搞定
South side covered.
南侧没问题
Maintain your guard.
保持警戒
Jack, Miko, Raphael,
杰克 神子 拉斐尔
I will have a clear view of you.
我会密切监控你们周围的情况
Once you secure the harvester,
只要拿到了收割器
I will contact Ratchet to bridge you back to base.
我就让救护车把你们传送回基地
I'll send you bypass all points of normal entry.
我送你们绕过所有的普通入口
You won't need to worry about setting off the alarm.
不用担心会触发警报器
But take care to avoid any security guards.
但千万别碰到什么保安
Oppa!
找到啦！
Sweet rims, 24-gage?
轮圈很帅嘛 24寸轮胎是吧？
You are really heavy duty,
你的分量还真够重的
just like my friend here.
和我这位朋友一样
It's Cons.
是虎子！
They got Optimus.
他们打倒了擎天柱
What?
什么？
Come on, time to make our exit, boys.
快走 该撤退了 兄弟们！
Uh, what's up?
呃…有事吗？
You'd better come with me, miss.
你最好跟我来 小姐
Not good.
坏了
Arcee!
阿尔茜！
It's Soundwave.
是声波！
Hmm... That would be game.
嗯 我的猎物是它
The Cons have the harbester.
虎子抢走了收割器！
And security has Miko!
保安抢走了神子！
What? I'm going in after her.
什么？我进去找她
Bulkhead, Miko may be detained,
隔板 神子可能被暂时扣留
but she is safe from harm.
但她没有任何危险
Look, kid, if this is some kind of a prank,
听着 小鬼 如果你在搞恶作剧
you need to know that the authorities are on their way.
告诉你 政府已经派人过来了
It'd go a whole lot easier for you if you just told me what happened to the sphere.
想尽快脱身的话 快告诉我那个金球去哪儿了？
I was researching my history report,
我要准备我的历史报告
I just lost track of time and got locked in here after closing.
结果忘了闭馆时间 就被关在里面了
So what's your history report about?
那你的历史报告是什么内容？
I'd love to know.
我很想知道
Eh...
呃…
In all likelihood Starscream will use the harvester to gather as much energon as quickly as he can
红蜘蛛极有可能使用收割器 迅速收集到巨大能量
from the planet's otherwise un-minable energon deposits.
他会选择星球上无法常规开采的能量矿
Approach with extreme caution.
一定要小心行动
Starscream will not hesitate to turn the harvester on any one of us.
红蜘蛛一定希望把收割器用在我们身上
Bulkhead,
隔板
it is best that you remain here.
你最好留在这里
So I can bust Miko out of the museum?
让我去博物馆救出神子吗？
So you can help Ratchet.
让你协助救护车
You may be Miko's guardian,
你虽然是神子的保镖
but she requires human assistance.
但眼下她需要的是人类的帮忙
Agent Fowler remains our best option.
最好请福勒探员走一趟
You've reached special Agent William Fowler.
这是威廉・福勒特工的电话号码
I'm currently on an intensive training retreat
我正在进行秘密强化训练
and I¡¯m not available until Tuesday.
周二之前不会回来
Still not answered.
还是无人接听
Fowler's lounging around some poolside cabana.
福勒肯定是在海景别墅享福呢
Bulkhead, I needed that!
隔板 那个我还有用呐！
We can free Miko,
我们能救出神子
if we can just return that harvester to the museum.
只要把收割器归还博物馆就行了
So that Decepticons can steal it all over again?
好让霸天虎再去偷走吗？
I am so dumb!
我真是笨到家了！
So how are we going to help Miko?
那我们该怎么帮神子？
By returning this replica to the museum,
把这个复制品还给博物馆
The construction of which would be going a whole lot faster
这东西本来很快就能做好了
if Bulkhead hadn't just mangled my frame wielder!
可隔板把我的车床砸了个稀烂！
We're already trespassers and thieves,
我们已经当过入侵者和窃贼了
why not add forgery to the list?
再加一条伪造罪也无所谓
I wish I had never taken Miko to the...
我真不该带神子去那个…
the painting of the harvester isn't the only thing we found in those ruins.
除了收割器的壁画 我们在遗迹还发现了别的东西
I'm sorry?
我没听懂
Starscream is not dumb.
红蜘蛛可不笨
No matter what kind of tool he has,
不管他有什么工具
he is going to take the easy route.
他总想走捷径
Why move maintains now,
干嘛还要去开山修路呢
when we have a motherload of energon right here for the taking,
手头上不是有这么多现成的能量吗？
courtesy of this gift from the ancient Autobots.
真要感谢古代汽车人留下的这份礼物
Uh, actually, commander Starscream,
呃 其实 红蜘蛛指挥官
it was a gift from breakdown and myself.
送礼的人是打击和在下
Oh, that energon, in such a tiny vessel.
喔 那么多能量 都收集在这个小容器里边
Those ancient Autobots never missed a trick, lord Starscream.
那帮远古的汽车人的确心灵手巧 红蜘蛛陛下
Um, scrap.
呃 糟了
Back for seconds.
去去就来！
You are a big one.
你个头很大
This could take a while.
吸收时间要长一点了
Wait, what are you doing?
等等 你要干嘛？
What I do best!
干我的老本行！
Breaking things!
拆东西！
He is a glutton for punishment.
他好像很喜欢接受惩罚
Fight?
打吗？
Um, drive.
嗯 撤吧
Hey.
嘿
And of course there is this whole principle of Deus ex Machina.
当然了 首先要知道什么是机器之神
Uh, the god from the machine.
呃 就是用机器制造的神
It's that part in Greek story telling when some character shows up out of the blue to make everything right.
在希腊戏剧里面 充当神的角色突然出现 解决所有问题
That's so, young lady.
是吗 小姑娘
Special Agent William Fowler,
我是特工威廉・福勒
the stolen property has been located and restored in museum premises.
失窃财产已经被找到 并归还给博物馆了
The girl comes with me.
这女孩我带走
You dropped you cell phone.
你的手机掉了
Found on the floor right next to your history report.
在地上找到的 就在你的历史报告旁边
Off you go.
你走吧
Good timing, Bulk.
来得正好 老隔！
I was running out of history factoids-
那些野史我都讲完了
-stuff I didn't even know I knew.
都快要编不下去了！
Looks like you are smarter than you led on?
看来你也有点开窍了
Under pressure.
压力就是动力
Me, too.
我也一样
Can't wait to finish my history report.
一定得赶快把历史报告写完
I'm gonna write all about how the Autobots interacted with ancient civilizations.
我要详细论述汽车人和古文明接触的那段历史
Uh, I'm not so sure that will get you into college, Miko.
呃 那个可不能保证你上大学 神子